# Rui Damas Cruzeiro Data Analyst, Portugal

+351 919 845 260 ruicruzeiro@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/ruicruzeiro

Currently finishing the Le Wagon Data Science Bootcamp in Lisbon to modernize and expand my skills. Former Civil Engineer with 10 years' experience in diverse roles, where gathering and analyzing data was vital to make decisions and report information. Looking for a career change to a purer Data Science role.

## Education

Data Science, bootcamp, Le Wagon, Lisbon (2022)

Project Management Professional (PMP), Project Management Institute (2013)

Business Management, post-graduate degree, ISEG School of Economics and Management, Lisbon (2013)

Civil Engineering, University of Coimbra (2006)

### Work history

# Property Value Analyst, 2017 – present

Companies: Fenacam (creditoagricola.pt), Coimbra District Court, private clients and 9 other appraisal companies

- Appraisal of flats, houses, stores, warehouses, hotels and lands for investment funds, city courts, private clients and bank mortgage loans for almost every major bank in Portugal.
- Property data was gathered daily and treated statistically to produce appraisal reports, fueling the desire to pursue a
  path in Data Science.
- Also issued Energy Performance Certificates of flats, houses and shops.
- Created the imostudio brand (imostudio.pt) for online business promotion.

## Cluster and Operations Manager, 2016 – 2018

MTD Pure Water (mtd.net)

- Coordinated design and setting up of technical solutions for temporary water and wastewater installations for the 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro and for 3 exhibition centers in Paris.
- Responsible for team leadership, planning, equipment requests and liaison with venue managers.
- For its delivery in the 2016 Olympics, MTD was awarded Best Operations Team at the Sports Business Awards 2017.

# Site and Supervision Manager in Civil Engineering, 2006 – 2016

Companies: Pengest (pengest.pt), Lena Group (grupolena.pt), Projectual (projectual.pt) and Serrialu (serrialu.com)

- Managed and supervised construction projects from 0,5 M€ to 31 M€ in Portugal, Algeria, Angola and France.
- Responsible for team leadership, planning, works coordination, invoicing, procurement, contract management, tendering and cost control.
- Throughout the projects, data was collected and treated to make decisions and to report financial performance.

#### Skills

IT: Python // SQL // Excel // AutoCAD // SketchUp

**Python toolkit:** NumPy // Pandas // Jupyter Notebook // Google Colab // Seaborn // SciPy // Streamlit **Machine Learning:** Scikit-Learn // Keras/Tensorflow

ML Ops: MLflow // Prefect // Docker // Google Cloud Platform

Languages: Portuguese (native) // English (fluent) // French (good) // Spanish (good)

#### Other activities

Radio broadcaster, Coimbra University Radio (2018 – present; also served as Treasurer between 2021 and 2022)

Translator, English to Portuguese translation of a collectible card edition about wildlife (2005 – 2006)

Math tutor, private tutoring for high school students (2003 – 2004)